Finding aid for the Bonnie Cashin Collection of Fashion, Theater, and Film Costume Design LSC.0440
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Publicity Materials and Citations, 1950-2000; 22 oversize boxes (151 folders)
  - Press Releases (Publicity), 1952 - 1977; 19 folders
    - Liberty of London announcement "About the Clothes" regarding Cashin's ready-to-wear collections., 1960 - 1961; 3 pages (Box 249, Folder 12)
    - From King Features Syndicate: "A Woman's New York" by Alice Hughes; "N.Y. Fashion Critics Award Five Stylists for Enhancing U.S. Fashion Supremacy.", September 28, 1961; 4 pages (Box 249, Folder 13)
    - From King Features Syndicate: "A Woman's New York" by Alice Hughes; "Newest Fur Tip: Wear an Un-Cut-Up Animal as a Stole or Throw, Daytime or Evening.", June 29, 1962; 2 pages (Box 249, Folder 14)
    - From King Features Syndicate: "A Woman's New York" by Alice Hughes; "Britain Cites Bonnie Cashin for Originality in Fashions.", November 4, 1964; 2 pages (Box 249, Folder 15)
    - From King Features Syndicate: "A Woman's New York" by Alice Hughes; "Food and Fashion are Global Forces of Communication.", May 14, 1965; 1 page (Box 249, Folder 16)
    - From The Milwaukee Journal, by Eleanor Coleman; untitled essay regarding Cashin's ready-to-wear designs., November 27, 1969; 2 pages (Box 249, Folder 17)
    - Poster-size monthly calendars featuring Cashin's ready-to-wear design illustrations for Sills and Co. and Russell Taylor Collections., 1976 - 1978; 5 posters (Box 294, Folder 7)
  - Museum / School Donations, Holdings and Exhibitions of Cashin Designs, ca. 1955 - 2001; 5 posters
    This subseries contains documentation of Bonnie Cashin's work collected and exhibited by museums and design schools.
    - Poster for Mitsukoshi, Nihonbashi, Tokyo exhibition "Celebrating 60 Years of American Style: A Coach Retrospective" curated by Stephanie Day Iverson., November 2001; 1 poster (Box 293, Folder 3)
    - Posters for Cashin appearances and exhibitions., ca. 1955 - 1991; 4 posters (Box 294, Folder 5)
  - Fashion Show Invitations, ca. 1957 - 2000; 2 folders
    This subseries contains invitations and publicity announcements for Bonnie Cashin fashion shows or related events.
    - Invitations for press and buyer showings of Cashin's ready-to-wear work., ca. 1960 - 1977; 53 pages (Box 135, Folder 41)
    - Publicity announcements for Cashin fashion shows, appearances, and Cashin-related lectures., ca. 1957 - 2000; 13 small posters (Box 292, Folder 9)
  - Bonnie Cashin Awards, 1950 - 1986; tbd (48 awards)
    This subseries contains Bonnie Cashin's awards for her clothing designs and philanthropic activities. Included are documents regarding these awards as well as the plaques or trophies given to Cashin.
    - Lists of Cashin's awards from mid-century through 1980s., 1976 - 1985; 2 pages (Box 247, Folder 1)
    - Honorary diplomas., ca. 1967 - 1983; 6 pages (Box 247, Folder 2)
      for participation in the Moscow International Fashion Festival 'The Good Look of Fashion, U.S.A", 1967; National Society of Literature and The Arts; Farifax County Public Schools Certificate of Appreciation, March 8, 1979; Kent State University Foundation, member of the Honorary Board of Advisors; Board of Trustees WNET / Thirteen Honor Roll certificate
    - Documents regarding Woolknit Design Awards, 1959, 1961 and 1980., 1961 - 1986; 4 pages (Box 247, Folder 3)
    - Documents regarding Neiman Marcus Award., 1950; 3 pages; 1 booklet (Box 247, Folder 4)
    - Documents regarding Coty Award., 1950; 1 page; 1 booklet (Box 247, Folder 5)
    - Documents regarding Sports Illustrated "Sporting Look" Award., 1958; 2 pages (Box 247, Folder 6)
    - Documents regarding Fashion Critics' Award., 1960; 1 page (Box 247, Folder 7)
    - Documents regarding Lord & Taylor's Salute to American Design., 1960; 1 page (Box 247, Folder 8)
    - Documents regarding Duns Scotus College (Detroit) "Salute to Women Who Work.", 1963; 8 pages (Box 247, Folder 9)
    - Documents regarding Sports Illustrated "Designer of the Year.", March 13 - May 6, 1963; 16 pages (Box 247, Folder 10)
    - Documents regarding London Sunday Times Award., August 6 - October 26, 1964; 34 pages (Box 247, Folder 12)
    - Documents regarding Republican Women in Industry and Professions "Salute to Women" honoring women selected for achievement in business, professions, and community service., October 3, 1964; 1 page (Box 247, Folder 13)
    - Documents regarding American Handbag Designer Award., May 22, 1968; 2 ribbons; 1 page; 1 brochure (Box 247, Folder 14)
    - Documents regarding Coty Return Award., June 21 - October 1, 1968; 28 pages; 1 booklet (Box 247, Folder 15)
    - Documents regarding Hallmark Company conference and exhibition., september 14, 1971 - January 7, 1974; 20 pages (Box 247, Folder 16)
    - Documents regarding Coty Hall of Fame Award., June 21 - October 19, 1972; 46 pages; 1 booklet (Box 248, Folder 1)
    - Documents regarding The American Fashion Awards., July 23, 1974 - March 19, 1975; 35 pages (Box 248, Folder 3)
    - Documents regarding Leather Industries of America American Designer Award., January 21 - April, 1976; 17 pages; 1 booklet (Box 248, Folder 6)
    - Documents regarding Anti-Defamation League "Women of Achievement in Fashion.", 1975; 1 booklet (Box 248, Folder 7)
    - Documents regarding Fashion Group International / Fashion Institute of Technology "Fifty Years of American Women in Fashion.", 1981; 3 pages; 2 booklets (Box 248, Folder 8)
    - Documents regarding Rhode Island University Athena Design's President's Fellows Award., April - June 1985; 10 pages (Box 248, Folder 9)
    - Documents regarding Cashin's nomination and induction into Fashion Walk of Fame., September 14, 1999 -; 2 pages (Box 248, Folder 10)
    - Honorary diploma from the Brooklyn Institute of Arts and Sciences and certificate from the Moscow International Fashion Show., April 12, 1951 and 1967; 3 pages (Box 292, Folder 8)
    - "The Neiman Marcus Award for Distinguished Service in the Field of Fashion.", September 4, 1950; 1 plaque (Box 300, Folder 1)
    - "Bonnie Cashin 1950 Awardee; Whose special genius for historical research has led not down academic halls, but into stardom in the field of fashion and costume design." (Neiman Marcus), September 4, 1950; 1 framed certificate (Box 300, Folder 2)
    - "The Philadelphia Fashion Group takes pleasure in honoring Bonnie Cashin as a creator of outstanding design and exhibitor in the 20th Century World of Fashions International Show, October 9, 1953, held to celebrate the opening of 20th Century Gallery., 1 framed certificate (Box 300, Folder 3)
      Costume Wing, Philadelphia Museum of Art
    - "A.S.D.A. Sports Illustrated 1956; Bonnie Cashin.", 1 medal (Box 300, Folder 4)
    - "The Commerce and Merchandise Division of The Lighthouse The New York Association for the Blind presents to Bonnie Cashin this Certificate of Appreciation for her generous contribution of outstanding (con't), November 14, 1957; 1 plaque (Box 300, Folder 5)
      designs to The Lighthouse Craftshop to help blind workers in their efforts to demonstrate their skill to the sighted world," presented at the Waldorf-Astoria
    - "Citation; On this day, the 3rd of June, 1959 the Philadelphia Museum college of Art Commends and Honors Bonnie Cashin for the distinction she has brought to her profession as one of the most inventive master-craftsmen of the fabulous world (cont.), June 3, 1959; 1 framed certificate (Box 300, Folder 6)
      of fashion. By her ingenious and tasteful fusion of the best fashion elements of many cultures to the special needs and spirit of our own time, she has brought the past closer to the present. Bonnie Cashin is a one-woman United Nations and she achieved this with the wise and subtle witchcraft of design."
    - "Design Award by Retail and Consumer Fashion Authorities of America for Woolknit Associates, Inc. to Bonnie Cashin: Special Merit for Creative Achievement in the Wool Knitwear Industry.", 1959; 1 plaque (Box 300, Folder 7)
    - "Lord & Taylor Salutes Bonnie Cashin for creative contributions to the continuing tradition of American Design.", 1960; 1 framed certificate (Box 300, Folder 8)
    - "Design Award by Retail and Consumer Fashion Authorities of America for Woolknit Associates, Inc. to Bonnie Cashin: Special Merit for Creative Achievement in the Wool Knitwear Industry.", 1961; 1 plaque (Box 300, Folder 9)
    - "The Lighthouse Award for Distinguished Service to Blind People; Bonnie Cashin; Her humanitarian spirit in recognition of capabilities of blind persons has been a source of inspiration to the blind worker (con't), October 19, 1961; 1 framed certificate (Box 301, Folder 1)
      "As a designer who has become famous for her exceptional use of textures in fashion, she has learned to rely greatly on the tactile properties of the fabrics with which she works. Knowing the importance of the sense of touch to the blind person, she has contributed designs created expressly for The Lighthouse part-time work center, thereby helping to increase employment opportunities and to motivate blind workers to greater achievement."
    - "Award to Bonnie Cashin for distinguished achievement presented at 'Salute to Women' Luncheon.", October 3, 1964; 1 framed certificate (Box 301, Folder 2)
    - "The New York Association for the Blind extends its heartfelt thanks to Bonnie Cashin for the help you have given so generously to The Lighthouse and the blind people it serves.", December 6, 1967; 1 framed certificate (Box 301, Folder 3)
    - "Presented to The Creator Bonnie Cashin by Saks Fifth Avenue.", September 16, 1969; 1 plaque (Box 301, Folder 4)
    - "Drexel University Nesbitt College of Design - Nutrition - Human Behavior - Home Economics presents its Honor Fashion Citation to Bonnie Cashin Recognizing with appreciation an ardent observer - intense participator - incisive discerner - con't., May 18, 1976; 1 diploma (Box 301, Folder 5)
      an elector of quality - an inventive master of form - designer par excellence - exemplar of what America stands for: living true to oneself. Given in this bicentennial year of our nation's history, nineteen hundred and seventy-six, on this eighteenth day of May."
    - "Thank you Bonnie Cashin for The Rendezvous with Elegance; The Salvation Army Auxiliary, Washington D.C.", September 30, 1977; 1 plaque (Box 301, Folder 6)
    - "Having Made Valuable and Significant Contributions to World Air Transport and to the Furtherance of International Understanding Bonnie Cashin is Hereby Appointed to Membership in The Clipper Club" (Pan American Airlines)., March 17, 1967; 1 framed certificate (Box 302, Folder 1)
    - "American Handbag Designer Award presented by The Leather Industries of America to Bonnie Cashin, Coach Leatherware for her contribution to the handbag and leather industries in creating and popularizing con't., May 22, 1968; 1 framed certificate (Box 302, Folder 1)
      "designs which have made good fashion and quality available to the mass market."
    - "I.Magnin Proudly Presents The Great American Award to Bonnie Cashin Whose Independent Spirit and Innovative Outlook Have Led American Women to Prize Her Uniquely Luxurious Sportswear." on mat: "All the Great Americans - All at I. Magnin", Fall 1974; 1 framed certificate (Box 302, Folder 3)
    - "Coty American Fashion Critics' Special Award 1961 to Bonnie Cashin.", 1 plaque
    - "Gold Needle Award presented to Bonnie Cashin; 1970; Mount Mary College - Heritage - Milwaukee - Designer Sponsorship.", 1 trophy
    - "Coty American Fashion Critics' Award 1972 presented to Bonnie Cashin.", 1 trophy
    - "Sports Illustrated Design Awards Designer of the Year Bonnie Cashin.", June 11, 1963; 1 trophy
    - "The Sporting Look Award; Bonnie Cashin.", May 28, 1958; 1 trophy
    - "The Sunday Times Special Fashion Award 1964 presented to Bonnie Cashin, U.S.A.", 1 crystal obelisk in presentation case
    - "The 1975 Fashion Awards; Furs; Bonnie Cashin for H.B.A. Furs.", 1 trophy
  - Catalogue Tear Sheets Featuring Cashin Designs, 1977 - Holiday 1987; 1 folder
    This subseries contains tear sheets from department and specialty store catalogues featuring Bonnie Cashin's clothing designs.
    - Tear sheets from retailers featuring Cashin's last ready-to-wear designs on the market., 1977 - Holiday 1987; 18 pages; 1 booklet (Box 292, Folder 1)
    - "Bonnie Cashin 1968 Fashion Award; Kaufmann's Pittsburgh.", 1 plaque
  - Bonnie Cashin at Events (Professional Photographs), 1950s - February 22, 1991; 3 oversize boxes and 2 folders
    - DVD: "Bonnie Cashin: Form Follows Function"; at Mount Mary College, February 22, 1991; 1 DVD (Box 240, Folder 5)
  - Innovative Design Fund (Legal Documents), 1979 - 1988; 9 oversize boxes and 2 folders
    This subseries contains documentation of Bonnie Cashin's Innovative Design Fund, a non-profit organization created by Cashin to fund design prototypes. The subseries is particularly rich in applications and documentation of I.D. Fund recipients' work.
    - Poster "Invitation to Innovative designers.", ca. 1980; 1 poster (Box 294, Folder 6)
- Cashin Men Ready-to-Wear, 1976; 1 folder
  This series contains documentation and illustrations of Bonnie Cashin's clothing designs for men. All illustrations and writings by Bonnie Cashin contained in this series are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
  - Sketches (Return to Ready-to-Wear), 1950 - Ca. 1953; 1 oversize box
    - Memos regarding and Cashin's illustrations of men's coat designs., October 17, 1976; 23 pages (Box 42, Folder 5)
- Knitwear Designs, 1952 - 1980; 21 oversize boxes (162 folders)
  This series contains Bonnie Cashin's records of her knitwear design contracts. The series is particularly rich in illustrations of her designed for Ballantyne cashmere and The Knittery. The series is subdivided by manufacturer: Guttman Brothers, Forstmann wool, Ballantyne, and the Knittery. All illustrations and writings by Bonnie Cashin contained in this series are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
  - Textile and Leather Swatches (Knitwear), ca. 1955; 1 folder
    This subseries contains swatches of materials selected by Bonnie Cashin for use in her ready-to-wear designs.
    - Swatches for use in Cashin's designs for Forstmann wool., ca. 1955; 6 swatches (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - Forstmann Wool; Coats and Suits, ca. 1951 - 1954; 1 oversize box
    This subseries contains Bonnie Cashin's design illustrations of coats and suits featuring Forstmann wool. All materials contained in this subseries are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
    - Cashin's pencil illustrations of ensembles featuring Forstmann wool., ca. 1951 - 1954; 5 illustrations (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - Cashin's pencil illustrations of ensembles featuring Forstmann wool., ca. 1951 - 1954; 20 illustrations (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - Cashin's pencil illustrations of ensembles featuring Forstmann wool., ca. 1951 - 1954; 19 illustrations (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - Cashin's hand-painted illustrations of ensembles featuring beige and ivory Forstmann wool., ca. 1951 - 1954; 7 illustrations (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - Cashin's hand-painted illustrations of ensembles featuring blue Forstmann wool., ca. 1951 - 1954; 5 illustrations (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - Cashin's hand-painted illustrations of ensembles featuring green Forstmann wool., ca. 1951 - 1954; 5 illustrations (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - Cashin's hand-painted illustrations of ensembles featuring black and white / gray Forstmann wool., ca. 1951 - 1954; 11 illustrations (Box 73, Folder 7)
    - Cashin's hand-painted illustrations of ensembles featuring mauve / plum Forstmann wool., ca. 1951 - 1954; 5 illustrations (Box 73, Folder 8)
    - Cashin's hand-painted illustration of an ensemble featuring orange Forstmann wool., ca. 1951 - 1954; 1 illustration (Box 73, Folder 9)
    - Cashin's hand-painted illustrations of ensembles featuring pink Forstmann wool., ca. 1951 - 1954; 3 illustrations (Box 73, Folder 10)
    - Cashin's hand-painted illustrations of ensembles featuring red Forstmann wool., ca. 1951 - 1954; 20 illustrations (Box 73, Folder 11)
    - Cashin's hand-painted illustrations of ensembles featuring brown Forstmann wool., ca. 1951 - 1954; 6 illustrations (Box 73, Folder 12)
    - Cashin's illustrations of ensembles featuring turquoise Forstmann wool., ca. 1951 - 1954; 12 illustrations (Box 73, Folder 13)
    - Cashin's hand-painted illustrations of ensembles featuring yellow Forstmann wool., ca. 1951 - 1954; 5 illustrations (Box 73, Folder 14)
  - Forstmann Wool: Sweaters, ca. 1955; 2 oversize boxes
    This subseries contains Bonnie Cashin's illustrations of sweater designs for manufacturer Forstmann wool. All materials contained in this subseries are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
    - Cashin's illustrations of designs featuring Forstmann wool., ca. 1955; 4 illustrations (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - Cashin's essay and illustrations of designs featuring Forstmann wool., ca. 1955; 6 pages (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - Cashin's illustrations of sweater designs for Forstmann wool., ca. 1955; 23 illustrations (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - Cashin's illustrations of sweater designs for Forstmann wool., ca. 1955; 20 illustrations (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - Cashin's illustrations of sweater designs for Forstmann wool., ca. 1955; 17 illustrations (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - Cashin's illustration of men's sweater design for Forstmann wool, titled "The Suburban.", ca. 1955; 1 illustration (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - Cashin's illustrations of sweater designs for Forstmann wool, mounted on board with swatches., ca. 1955; 23 illustrations (Box 75, Folder 1)
  - Guttman Brothers, ca. 1952 - 1954; 1 oversize box and 1 folder
    This subseries contains Bonnie Cashin's illustrations of knitwear designs for manufacturer Guttman Brothers. The subseries also includes photographs featuring Cashin's designs. All illustrations by Bonnie Cashin contained in this subseries are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
    - Black and white photographs of Cashin's designs of knit outfits for Guttman Bros., 1952 - 1954; 26 photographs (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Cashin's illustrations of knit ensembles designed for Guttman Brothers., ca. 1952 - 1954; 15 illustrations (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - Cashin's illustrations of knit ensembles designed for Guttman Brothers., ca. 1952 - 1954; 22 illustrations (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - Cashin's illustrations of knit beachwear designed for Guttman Brothers., ca. 1952 - 1954; 24 illustrations (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - Cashin's illustrations of knit ensembles designed for Guttman Brothers., ca. 1952 - 1954; 15 illustrations (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - Cashin's illustrations of knit ensembles designed for Guttman Brothers., ca. 1952 - 1954; 9 illustrations (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - Cashin's illustrations of knit ensembles designed for Guttman Brothers., ca. 1952 - 1954; 15 illustrations (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - Cashin's illustrations of knit ensembles designed for Guttman Brothers., ca. 1952 - 1954; 28 illustrations (Box 71, Folder 7)
    - Cashin's illustrations of knit ensembles designed for Guttman Brothers., ca. 1952 - 1954; 9 illustrations (Box 71, Folder 8)
    - Cashin's illustrations of knit ensembles with leather, a collaborative collection for Guttman Bros and Sills and Co., ca. 1953; 14 illustrations (Box 71, Folder 9)
  - Ballantyne; Cashmere Designs, 1964 - 1968; 4 oversize boxes and 2 folders (45 folders total)
    This subseries contains documentation of Bonnie Cashin's cashmere garment designs for manufacturer Ballantyne. The subseries is particularly rich in Cashin's design illustrations and also includes photographs and slides of her designs. All illustrations and writing by Bonnie Cashin contained in this subseries are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
    - Art selected by Cashin for use as sweater motifs., ca. 1964; 5 pages (Box 85, Folder 1)
    - Cashin's illustrations of and documents regarding sweater designs., 1964; 13 illustrations (Box 85, Folder 2)
    - Cashin's illustrations of sweater designs for Ballantyne of Peebles., 1964; 6 illustrations (Box 85, Folder 3)
    - Cashin's illustrations of sweater designs for Ballantyne of Peebles., 1964; 23 illustrations (Box 85, Folder 4)
    - Cashin's illustrations of sweater designs for Ballantyne of Peebles., ca. 1964 - 1965; 25 illustrations (Box 85, Folder 5)
    - Cashin's illustrations of sweater designs for Ballantyne of Peebles., ca. 1964 - 1965; 25 illustrations (Box 85, Folder 6)
    - Cashin's illustrations of sweater designs for Ballantyne of Peebles., ca. 1964 - 1967; 22 illustrations (Box 85, Folder 7)
    - Cashin's illustrations of sweater designs marketed by Sills and Co., ca. 1968; 17 illustrations (Box 95, Folder 1)
    - Cashin's illustrations of sweater designs for Ballantyne of Peebles; discarded from line., February 1968; 6 illustrations (Box 95, Folder 2)
    - Cashin's illustrations of sweater designs for Ballantyne of Peebles, in triplicate., February 1968; 24 illustrations (Box 95, Folder 3)
    - Cashin's illustrations of sweater designs for Ballantyne of Peebles., March 1968; 27 illustrations (Box 95, Folder 4)
    - Cashin's illustrations of sweater designs for Ballantyne of Peebles., ca. 1968; 31 illustrations (Box 95, Folder 5)
    - Cashin's illustrations of sweater designs for Ballantyne of Peebles titled "Cashmere cut and sew.", ca. 1968; 7 illustrations (Box 95, Folder 6)
    - Cashin's illustrations of sweater designs for Ballantyne of Peebles., ca. 1968; 7 illustrations (Box 95, Folder 7)
    - Cashin's illustrations of sweater designs for Ballantyne of Peebles., ca. 1964 - 1965; 12 illustrations (Box 99, Folder 2)
    - Cashin's illustrations of sweater designs for Ballantyne of Peebles including group labeled "Cashmere travel plot.", 1968; 9 illustrations (Box 99, Folder 3)
    - Cashin's paintings of sweater bodies used for her Ballantyne Cashmere designs., ca. 1964 - 1965; 37 paintings (Box 109, Folder 1)
    - Slides: Cashin's knitwear designs for Ballantyne, modeled in Cashin's apartment and studio., ca. 1964; 14 slides (Box 131, Folder 6)
    - Slides: Workers and models wearing Cashin's designs at Ballantyne., August 1966; 17 slides (Box 131, Folder 10)
    - Slides: Cashin's designs for Ballantyne, modeled in Cashin's studio and unknown workroom., ca. 1965; 19 slides (Box 131, Folder 11)
    - Slides: Ballantyne facility and employees., August 1967; 25 slides (Box 131, Folder 14)
    - Cashin's essays regarding cashmere design., 1965 - 1966; 24 pages (Box 182, Folder 1)
    - Memos and correspondence regarding Cashin's knitwear designs., 1967; 16 pages (Box 182, Folder 2)
    - Photographs of Ballantyne headquarters, manufacturing processes, employees, and visit from the British royal family., ca. 1965; 97 photographs (Box 182, Folder 3)